Live for danger. Fight for justice. Pray for mercy.
Puss in Boots is a animation, family, fantasy film directed by Chris Miller.
Long before he even met Shrek, the notorious fighter, lover and outlaw Puss in Boots becomes a hero when he sets off on an
adventure with the tough and street smart Kitty Softpaws and the mastermind Humpty Dumpty to save his town.
This is the true story of The Cat, The Myth, The Legend...
Puss in Boots (voice), played by Antonio Banderas.
Kitty Softpaws (voice), played by Salma Hayek Pinault.
Humpty Dumpty (voice), played by Zach Galifianakis.
Jack (voice), played by Billy Bob Thornton.
Jill (voice), played by Amy Sedaris.
Imelda (voice), played by Constance Marie.
Puss in Boots is a 2011 American animated  adventure comedy film featuring the
titular character from Shrek 2 (2004) and inspired by the fairy tale.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, the film was directed by
Chris Miller and written by Tom Wheeler.
Antonio Banderas stars as Puss in Boots, alongside Salma Hayek, Zach
Galifianakis, Billy Bob Thornton, and Amy Sedaris.
The film follows the origin story of Puss in
Boots, before the events of Shrek 2.
Accompanied by his friends, Humpty Dumpty and Kitty Softpaws, Puss is pitted against Jack and Jill, two murderous outlaws, for ownership
of three legendary magical beans that lead to a great fortune of Golden Eggs from the Great Terror, a gigantic Goose.
Development began following the release of Shrek 2 in 2004.
Originally titled Puss in Boots: The Story of an Ogre Killer, it was announced
as a direct-to-video film, scheduled to be released in 2008.
In October 2006, the film was redeveloped as a theatrical release, with
Shrek the Third (2007) director Miller joining the project.
Puss in Boots had its world premiere on October 16, 2011, aboard the cruise ship Allure of the Seas,
and was released in theaters in the United States on October 28 by Paramount Pictures.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing $555
million on a production budget of $130 million.
At the 84th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Animated Feature.
A television series spin-off, The Adventures of Puss in Boots, premiered in January
2015, and a sequel, Puss in Boots: The Last Wish, was released in 2022.
The film explores themes of small town, fairy tale, rebel, spin off, wild west.
The tone is lighthearted.